💌 exgin3538@gmail.com 🔇 https://samuelreid.netlify.app/ 📞 (770) 899 - 5056 💡 Atlanta, Georgia 🛚 in sreid20 🖸 exgin

ABOUT ME

The challenge of developing a program from the ground up sparked my interest in being a Software Engineer. The feeling of finally being able to solve a bug or learn a new way to implement code is extremely rewarding for me. This lead me to gain experience developing full stack web applications with modern frameworks and technologies.

SKILLS

Programming Languages	Front End	Back End	Databases
Python	Bootstrap 4	Flask	MySQL
Java	React	NodeJS	PostgreSQL
JavaScript	Redux	ExpressJS	MongoDB
Python	Bulma	Django	SQLite
⊔тмі			

Version Control & Deployment

CSS PHP

Git Github Heroku Netlify

Testing Libraries

lasmine Supertest

React Testing Library

Additional Techniques

Creating RESTful APIs Writing unit & integration tests Making authentication and authorization Applying OOP Following TDD

PROJECTS

08/2020 - 08/2020 **Black Lives Matter**

- Created a Full Stack website to inform users on the current civil crisis happening
- Developed a backend API to handle secret API keys & routes needed
- Inform user's on how they can help & support the cause
- Stack Used: ReactJS /w Material UI & Bootstrap, Redux, NodeJS /w ExpressJS, PostgreSQL

One Stop Skate Spot - Skate Park Locator

05/2020 - 05/2020

- Created a Full Stack website application using various API's to create a skateboarding website for all skill levels
- Developed a small backend API utilized for querying needed data for the map
- Collected data from Yelp's API to view the closest location needed for the user
- Stack Used: JavaScript w/ jQuery & Bootstrap, Python w/ Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

Springboard -

Software Engineering Career Track Fellow

02/2020 -Present

- Developed 2 personal capstone projects to refine and enhance my technical skills
- Completing 800+ hours of software engineering curriculum and training while working with established industry experts
- Mastering skills within front-end web development, back-end web development, and full stack development

UPS - Package Handler & Sorter -Forest Park, GA

11/2018 -12/2019

• Managed the loading and sorting for over 2500+ packages to ensure that customers receive the correct packages, intact, and on time

• Trained 10+ new hires as package handlers and sorters to help them acclimate to the environment and ramp up quickly on the job to assist the team

Recreational Center: Jim Huie -

09/2019 -

Rec. Lifeguard - Jonesboro, GA • Responsible for the supervising & monitoring the safety of the 50+ of patrons

- Administering emergency oxygen, first aid, CPR, AED if required for any life threatening situations

DUA Fayetteville - Server -Fayetteville, GA

10/2017 -05/2018

- Ensured excellent interpersonal skills.
- Maintained professional working relationships with colleagues, customers, and

EDUCATION

Clayton State University

08/2017 - 12/2019

Associates Information Technology